A Guide to the John D. Chapla Papers, 1972-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John D. Chapla Papers, 1972-2013
The Library of Virginia
51115
22.4 cubic feet (51 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John D. Chapla, Alexandria.
Biographical Information
John David Chapla was born on 6 June 1947 in Cleveland, Ohio. He graduated from the Virginia Military Institute with a degree in English in 1968, and then served in Vietnam with the 173rd Airborne Brigade as an infantry officer and as a public affairs officer during his 22 years in the Army. He earned a master's degree in journalism from the University of North Carolina in 1978. In 1990, Chapla joined the staff of the United States House Armed Services Committee, and served for 24 years. He was a Civil War historian, and authored three books for the Virginia Regimental Histories Series. Chapla died in Alexandria, Virginia on 5 January 2014, and is buried in Arlington National Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1972-2013, of John D. Chapla (1947-2014) of Alexandria, Virginia, containing his research files compiled while writing books on the 42nd, 48th, and 50th Virginia Infantry Regiments for the Virginia Regimental Histories Series, miscellaneous subject files, and his research on Alexander Welch Reynolds (1816-1876) for articles which he co-authored.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. 42nd, 48th, and 50th Virginia Infantry Regiments Research Files.
Series II. Miscellaneous Subject Files.
Series III. Alexander Welch Reynolds Research Files.
Contents List
- Series I. 42nd, 48th, and 50th Virginia Infantry Regiments Research Files., Extent: 34 boxes. (Box 1-29, 47-51)
  The research files on the 42nd, 48th, and 50th Virginia Infantry regiments include notes, transcriptions, and copies of materials from numerous archival repositories, mainly the National Archives and Library of Congress, and from collections held privately by other researchers and descendants of Confederate soldiers. Some of the sources include census records, court records, compiled service records and other military records, published works, information from various Civil War websites and message boards, maps and photographs. There are also chronologies of operations and rosters for each regiment compiled by Chapla. There is a good deal of information on John Dudley Greever (1836-1924), William McCauley (1837-1908), and Fleming Saunders (1829-1907). The research files were compiled by Chapla for his article "Quartermaster Operations in the Forty-Second Virginia Infantry Regiment," which appeared in the March 1984 issue of Civil War History, and later for books published for the Virginia Regimental Histories Series. Also included in this series is information on Jesse Spinner Burks (1823-1885), which Chapla used for a sketch written for the Dictionary of Virginia Biography. Some of the folders include source citation numbers written on the left margin. There is a key to the sources contained in the files for each regiment.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - 42nd Virginia Infantry Regiment
    - A & IGO/ANVA - General and Special Orders. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, John Quincy. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ancestry.com. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anthony Family Papers - UVA. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Antietam - Carman Manuscript and Maps, The Rock Ledge. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Asa Tennet Letters. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bartlett - Military Record of Louisiana. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bassett Historical Center Symposium, 7 March 2009. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bedford County Records. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bidgood Rosters. (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - Bigelow - Campaign of Chancellorsville. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Brock, Robert A. - Hardesty's Historical and Geographical Encyclopedia Iluustrated - Special Virginia Edition - Amherst and Bedford Counties Volume. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Brock, Robert A. - Virginia and Virginians. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Buford, John Quincy Adams. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Bunch, Jack - Roster of Confederate Courts-Martial. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Burks, Jesse Spinner - Dictionary of Virginia Biography. (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - Calendar of Virginia State Papers. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "The Campbell Crier". (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Campbell County Records. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Casualties. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Casualties - Co. G (Card File). (Box 51, Folder n/a)
    - Cemetery Records. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Chapla, John D. - Bluford Abel Presentation (Lee School, Manhattan, Kansas), 1984. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chapla, John D. - Notes, Computations, Statistics on the 42nd. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chapla, John D. - Original 42nd Virginia Manuscript - 1st Edition. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chapla, John D. - "Quartermaster Operations in the 42nd Virginia Infantry," Civil War History - Drafts and Related Material. (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Chapman Family Notes. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chronology - 42nd Virginia Infantry: 1861-1863 - Draft. (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
    - Cooper, H.C. - Personal Collection. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Diuguid Records - Jerald H. Markham. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns Family Notes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dalton, Hamon C.. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Deyerle Family Notes. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Eagle, Robert Anderson. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Eggleston-Stultz Family (Kermon Thomasson). (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Encyclopedia of Virginia Biography. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ferguson, Chris - Confederate Dead at Hollywood Cemetery. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Find A Grave. (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Floyd County Records. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Footnote.com. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fort Delaware Society. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 42nd Virginia - 2nd Edition Updates. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 42nd Virginia - 3rd Edition Updates. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 42nd Virginia - 4th Edition Updates. (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - 42nd Virginia - Color Guard Notes. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 42nd Virginia - Correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
    - 42nd Virginia - Photographs. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 42nd Virginia - Reenactors. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 42nd Virginia - Roster Sources. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 42nd Virginia - Speech, 1 November 1994. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Franklin, Charles Calloway. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Franklin County Records. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Frantz, Marshall P.. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - S. Bassett French Papers. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Gravely, Peyton B.. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Griggs Family Papers. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Griggs, William J.. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Co. H/42nd Virginia Muster Roll (Partial) - VHS. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hairston, Elizabeth Seawell. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Hammond, Wesley A. - Diary. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Harris Family Notes. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Hatcher, Henry M.. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hatcher, William H.. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Henry County - Bassett Historical Center. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Henry County Records. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hewitt, Richard Newton. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Holland, Asa. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hotchkiss, Jedediah. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Howard, H. E.. (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Hunter, John Harrison. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Hutchinson, Scott. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Kagey, Henry. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Kefauver, Richard Perrin. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Kent, Nannie E.. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Krick, Robert E.L.. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Langhorne Family. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Leftwich Family. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Leigh, Benjamin Watkins. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Letters - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 1. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Letters - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 2. (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - Letters - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 3. (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
    - Levstik, Frank R. - Master's Thesis. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Library of Congress - Journals of the Confederate Congress. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Library of Congress - Records of the Confederate States of America. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Library of Virginia - R.E. Lee Camp Soldiers' Home Applications. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Maddox Family. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Maps. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Maryland Historical Society. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mays, Thomas - Roanoke College During the Civil War. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - McCauley Family Letters. (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - McCauley Family Papers (John W. McCauley). (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - McCauley Papers Donation. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - McCauley, William - Diaries. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - McCauley, William - Library of Virginia. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Reflections on the Life and Times of William McCauley and Margaret Jane McCauley" by John W. McCauley. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - McCauley, William - Roanoke Valley Historical Society. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - McCauley, William - Southern Historical Collection. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - McCauley, William - University of Virginia. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Medical and Surgical History of the Civil War. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Meire, Dr. William Stack. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Articles. (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
    - Mount Sharon (Orange County, VA). (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mullins, Samuel J.. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Museum of the Confederacy - Photographs. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - National Archives - Confederate Service Records - North Carolina. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - National Archives - Lost Appomattox Roster (RG109). (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - National Archives - Notes on 42nd Virginia Compiled Service Records. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Nichols, Mahlon P.. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Officers Roster. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Official Records of the War of the Rebellion. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Operations of the 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 1. (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Operations of the 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 2. (Box 9, Folder 9-12)
    - Operations of the 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 3. (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
    - Operations of the 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 4. (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
    - Patrick County Death Register. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Patrick County Historical Society. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Patrick County Records. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Pay Roll Bounty, Lt. Charles W. Hardy, Co. G. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Penn, Thomas G. and John C.. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Puckett, Henry Douglas. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Quartermaster Information. (Box 10, Folder 11-14)
    - Research Sources (Key). (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Ritter, Ben. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Roanoke County Records. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Rockingham County Tombstones. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Roster - 24th Virginia Infantry (Co. H). (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Roster - 42th Virginia Infantry - First Edition (Card File). (Box 49-50, Folder n/a)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 1. (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 2. (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Vol. 3. (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry - By Company. (Box 47, Folder n/a)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry - Co. G (Card File). (Box 51, Folder n/a)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry, Co. G (A-L). (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Roster - 42nd Virginia Infantry, Co. G (M-Z). (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Roster, Capt. W.W. Morris, Co. G. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roster, Capt. John E. Penn, Co. H. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Roster of Ex-Confederate Soldiers and Sailors Living in Henry County. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ruffner, Kevin. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Irvine-Saunders Family Papers - UVA. (Box 12, Folder 7-10)
    - Saunders, Fleming. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 7th Indiana re: 42nd Virginia at Gettysburg. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Shelton, P.F.. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Stuart's Horse Artillery Camp #1784. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Taliaferro, William B.. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Thomas, Christopher Y.. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Thomas, Don P.. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Thomas Jefferson University Archives. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Tice, James R.. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Tompkins, James L.. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Union Theological Seminary - Deceased Alumni Files. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - United Confederate Veterans - Garland-Rodes Camp. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - University of Virginia (Anthony Family). (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Confederate Pensions. (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
    - Virginia Historical Society - Saunders Family Papers. (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
    - "Virginia in the Civil War" Message Board. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Law Register. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Virgina Magazine of History and Biography. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Military Institute. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Walton, S.W.. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - The War: "Stonewall" Jackson, His Campaign and Battles, The Regiment, As I Saw Them by James H. Wood. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - War Between the States (Memorabilia). (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Washington and Lee University. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Winn, Andrew J.. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Wright, Allen W.. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Wright, Allen W. - "Company I, Campbell Guards". (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Wright, Allen W. - "The 42nd Virginia Infantry". (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
  - 48th Virginia Infantry Regiment
    - Addington Notes. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - AWOLs and Deserters. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Bell Family Notes. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Bidgood Roster - 48th Virginia Infantry - LVA. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Biographical Directory of the United States Congress. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Biographical Register of Members Virginia State Convention of 1861. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Blackwell Family Letters and Papers. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Blue & Gray. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Boatwright Papers - UNC. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Bond, Vernard. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Buchanan, Samuel T.. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Calendar of Virginia State Papers. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Casada, James A.. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Casualties. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Cemetery Records. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Census - 1910 - Smyth and Washington Counties - CSA Veterans. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Chronology - 48th Virginia Infantry. (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - Clark-Buchanan Family Letters - LVA. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Cleek, James D.. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Cocke-Cox Family Notes. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Coleman Family Papers. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Compiled Service Records. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence. (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - Courts-martial. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Darnell-Carter Family Notes. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Deaths. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Dempsey Family Notes. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Descriptions, Physical. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Eberle Family Papers. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Elam, William P.. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Enlistments. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Enlistments - Union Service. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Find A Grave. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Fleenor Family Notes. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Frazier Family Notes. (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Garnett Family Letters. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Garnett, Thomas Stuart - FNMP. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Garnett, Thomas Stuart - National Archives. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Gate City Herald (Scott County). (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Gollehon Family Notes. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Greever, James S.. (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - Hardesty's Historical and Geographical Encyclopedia. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Harman, John Newton, Sr. - Annals of Tazewell County, Virginia. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Harris, David Harvey. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Hartsock-McConnell Family Notes and Letters. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Hatfield Papers. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Horn, Glennis - Lambert-Hinkle-Hall Family Papers. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Howard, H.E.. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Huntington Library - C.R. Skinker Letters. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Hurst, Patricia J. - History and People of Clark Mountain. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Hurst, Patricia J. - Rapidan River Area of Clark Mountain. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Increase in Excellence. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Ireson Family Records. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Items Needing Input to Files. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Johnson, Andrew Jackson. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Journal-Virginian (Abingdon). (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Kagey, Henry. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - King, John R. - "My Experience in the Confederate Army and in Northern Prisons". (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Krick, Robert. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Lee Family Papers and Notes. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Lemley, Jacob - Diary. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Letters - 48th Virginia Infantry. (Box 17, Folder 3-7)
    - Library of Virginia - AWOL Notice. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Library of Virginia - R.E. Lee Camp Home Applications. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Logistics Operations. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Lynchburg Daily-Virginian. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "The Meadows" (Washington County, VA). (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miller, Ann L. - Antebellum Orange. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Articles and Correspondence. (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Nash Family Notes. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - National Archives - AIGO/ANVA General Orders and Special Orders. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - National Archives - AIGO Special Orders. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - National Archives - Compiled Service Records of Confederate General and Staff Officers and Non-Regimental Enlisted Men. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - National Archives - Inspection Reports. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - National Archives - Letters Received by the Adjutant and Inspector General Office. (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - National Archives - Manuscripts (incl. 42nd and 50th Virginia Infantry). (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - National Archives - Muster Rolls. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - National Archives Orders and Documents. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - National Archives - Record of Events from Unit Muster Rolls. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - No Separate Files - Rosters. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Occupations/Careers. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Officers. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Official Records of the War of the Rebellion. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Pension Applications - Library of Virginia. (Box 18, Folder 14-16)
    - Peters Family Notes. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Photograph - 25th Virginia Infantry. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Photographs. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Quarles, Garland R., et. al. - Diaries, Letters, and Recollections of the War Between the States. (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Quartermaster Operations. (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - Ratliff Family Notes. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Reenlistment Leaves, 1862. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Ben Ritter Collection - Handley Library. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Robertson, Francis Smith. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Roll of Honor - Museum of the Confederacy. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Roster. (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
    - Roster - 48th Virginia Infantry - First Edition. (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - Roster - 48th Virginia Infantry - Second Edition (Surname B). (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - Roster - 48th Virginia Infantry - Vol. 1. (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
    - Roster - 48th Virginia Infantry - Vol. 2. (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
    - Russell County Death Index, 1861. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Russell County, VA Website. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Fleming Saunders Papers - Duke University. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Sources (Key). (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Southern Historical Society Papers. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Southwest Virginia Historical Society. (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Speer Family Notes. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Stroud, David V.. (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Summers, Lewis Preston - History of Southwest Virginia. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Tennessee Confederate Pension Applications. (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Texas Pension Applications. (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Thompson Family Notes. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Toney, Marcus B. - Diary. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Townsend Family Notes. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 24th Michigan Infantry. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - U.D.C. Applications. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Valley Brass Band Article. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Fielden C. Vaughan Papers. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - John M. Vermillion Papers. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Vineyard Papers - LVA. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Vipperman Family Notes. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Historical Society. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Virginia in the Civil War" Message Board. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Military Institute Archives. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Washington County Historical Society. (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Washington County Records. (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Weddle Family Papers. (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Winchester Evening Star. (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Yeary, Mamie - Reminiscences of the Boys in Gray. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - 50th Virginia Infantry Regiment
    - AIGO/ANVA General Orders and Special Orders. (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - AWOLs/Deserters/Courts-martial. (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - John P. Alderman Collection. (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Allen, James Davis. (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Amherst County Historical Museum. (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Amherst County Sources. (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - The Amherst County Story. (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Appleton's Cyclopaedia of American Biography. (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Baldwin Family Notes. (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Barnard Family Papers. (Box 20, Folder 28-29)
    - Baxter, Dr. Oscar F.. (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Biographical Directory of the American Congress. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Bridges Papers. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Buchanan-Graham Family Letters. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Burchett Family Notes. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Carroll County Sources. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Casualties. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Cemetery Records. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Chambers, Charles E. - Virginia Confederates in Texas. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 5 Revisions. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Chicago Historical Society - Terry's Brigade. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Chronology - 50th Virginia Infantry - Vol 1: 1861-1862. (Box 21, Folder 11-14)
    - Chronology - 50th Virginia Infantry - Vol 2: 1863-1865. (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
    - Chronology - 50th Virginia Infantry - Vol 2: 1863-1865. (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Cincinnati Enquirer. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Clothing Requisitions. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Coghill, James Lindsay. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Commanders. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Compiled Service Records - Research Notes. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Cox Family Letters. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Cross, Dr. David F.. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Davis Family Papers. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Deatherage Family Notes. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Duff Family Papers. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Early Settlers of Lee County, Virginia and Adjacent Counties. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Enlistments. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Enlistments in U.S. Military. (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Find A Grave. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Gillespie Letters. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Grayson County Historical Society. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Grayson County Pension Board. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Grayson County Sources. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Greever Family Letters - Transcriptions by Kevin C. Ruffner. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Greever Family Papers. (Box 23, Folder 6-11)
    - Ray W. Gunn Files. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Hefflefinger, Henry A.. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - The Historical Shop. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Histories of the Several Regiments From North Carolina in the Great War... Walter Clark, ed. (Vol. 2). (Box 48, Folder n/a)
    - History and Roster - Footnoted Version. (Box 23, Folder 15-17)
    - Howard, Harold E. - Miscellaneous Files. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hutchinson, Scott. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Jessup, Elijah. (Box 24, Folder 3)